Guide to the Springside Landscape Restoration Records, 1870-2024 (bulk 1972-2017)
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Springside Landscape Restoration Records
1870-2024
1972-2017
Springside Landscape Restoration
11 cubic feet (13 boxes)
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
This collection consists of administrative and financial records, correspondence, and photographs created by Springside Landscape Restoration, a non-profit organization dedicated to the preservation and maintenance of Springside--a United States National Historic Site and the summer home of Matthew Vassar (1792-1868). Publications and writings about Springside and its designer, landscape architect Andrew Jackson Downing (1815-1852), as well as records related to Springside from its 20th-century owners, the Nelson family, are also included.
Historical Note
The property called "Springside" was purchased by Matthew Vassar (1792-1868) in 1850, who hired notable American landscape architect Andrew Jackson Downing (1815-1852) to design the property as an ornamental farm over the next two years. The landscape and buildings were constructed based on Downing's designs over the next several years and it served as Matthew Vassar's summer home until his death in 1868. With no direct heirs and no instructions in his will as to what should become of the property, Springside changed hands several times before being purchased at auction in 1879 by William Nelson. The property remained with the Nelson family for almost a century, but by the 1960s it had fallen into disrepair and only one building, the Porter's Lodge, remained fully intact. The property was photographed by Rollie McKenna and in 1969 Springside was added to the United States National Register of Historic Places. Despite this historical site status, in 1982 developer Springside Associates (later Springside Condominiums, Inc.) received approval from the City of Poughkeepsie to build a luxury condominium complex on the historic property. This galvanized local preservationists, including Vassar faculty member Harvey Flad and local nonprofit organizations Dutchess County Landmarks Association and Hudson River Sloop Clearwater, Inc., to petition the City of Poughkeepsie to have an environmental assessment of the property conducted and to deny Springside Associates permission to build on the property.
Springside Landscape Restoration (SLR) was formed in 1984 as part of a compromise between the preservationists, Springside Associates, and the City of Poughkeepsie. It was officially chartered as an educational non-profit by the New York State Department of Education in 1987. Part of the compromise included a subdivision of the property, with the parcel determined to be the most historic portion officially deeded to SLR in 1990. SLR has since maintained the property and undertaken a number of projects to conserve and restore Andrew Jackson Downing's original vision, including repainting and the Porter's Lodge, clearing almost 20 acres of secondary growth that was not part of Downing's vision, and protecting the site from potentially destructive development projects.
Scope and Content Note
This collection consists of administrative and financial records, correspondence, and photographs created by Springside Landscape Restoration, a non-profit organization dedicated to the preservation and maintenance of Springside--a United States National Historic Site and the summer home of Matthew Vassar (1792-1868). Publications and writings about Springside and its designer, landscape architect Andrew Jackson Downing (1815-1852), as well as records related to Springside from its 20th-century owners, the Nelson family, are also included.
Arrangement
The collection is organized into seven series: Series I. Administrative Files, 1982-2019; Series II. Grants, 1987-2005; Series III. Photographs, 1972-2006; Series IV. Site Plans and Maps, 1983-2000; Series V. Proposals, Reports, and Surveys, 1972-2023; Series VI. Writings and Publications, 1950-2017; and Series VII. Nelson Family Papers, 1870-2024.
Access
Series I. Administrative Files contains one restricted file. The rest of the collection is open for research according to the
regulations of the Vassar College Archives and Special Collections Library
without any additional restrictions.
Related Materials
Harvey Flad Papers
The Rosalie "Rollie" Thorne McKenna Papers include materials related to Springside's inclusion in the National Register of Historic Places, including correspondence with the National Park Service and photographs of Springside taken by McKenna in 1968.
Matthew Vassar Papers
Subject Headings
Names:
Downing, A. J. (Andrew Jackson), 1815-1852; Flad, Harvey K., 1938-; Vassar, Matthew, 1792-1868
Organizations:
National Historic Landmarks Program (U.S.); New York (State). Office of Parks, Recreation, and Historic Preservation; Poughkeepsie (N.Y.). Common Council
Subjects:
Historic preservation--New York (State); Historic sites--Conservation and restoration--New York (State); Historic gardens--New York (State)
Places:
Poughkeepsie (N.Y.)
Document Types:
Archaeological objects; Audiocassettes; Audiovisual materials; Clippings (information artifacts); Compact discs; Correspondence; Financial records; Minutes (administrative records); Negatives (photographs); Newsletters; Photographs; Printed ephemera; Property records; Site plans
VCL Categories:
Local History; Vassar College
Encoding Information
Encoded by Emma Gronbeck, June 2024.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Springside Landscape Restoration, June 2021. (M2021-007)
Series VII. Nelson Family Papers was the gift of Miles Nelson, May 2024. (M2024-009)
Series List
- Series I. Administrative Files, 1982-2019; (Boxes 1-5)
  This series contains correspondence, meeting minutes, vital records, financial records, maintenance and planning records, and other materials related to the founding and operation of Springside Landscape Restoration (SLR). Included are records related to the creation of SLR in response to the proposed condominium project neighboring Springside in 1982, including communications between the City of Poughkeepsie Planning Board, Dutchess County Landmarks Association, Hudson River Sloop Clearwater, Inc., Springside Associates (later Springside Condominiums, Inc.).
  Arranged alphabetically by title.
- Series II. Grants, 1987-2005; (Box 5)
  This series contains grant applications, correspondence with granting organizations, and other materials related to grants and other monetary awards that Springside Landscape Restoration applied for.
  Arranged alphabetically by title, with a chronology of grants filed at the beginning of the sequence and general research filed at the end.
- Series III. Photographs, 1972-2006; (Box 6)
  This series contains photographic materials--including prints, negatives, and slides--of Springside and Springside Landscape Foundation activities, including cleanup projects, site documentation, and plant sales.
  Arranged chronologically.
- Series IV. Site Plans and Maps, 1983-2000; (Boxes 6, 11-13)
  This series contains site plans and maps of Springside, predominantly those created as part of Robert M. Toole's 1985 survey of the property and Walmsley & Company, Inc.'s 1988 survey.
  Organized alphabetically by creator, with miscellaneous plans filed at the end. Sub-arranged alphabetically by title.
- Series V. Proposals, Reports, and Surveys, 1972-2023; (Boxes 6-8, 10)
  This series contains surveys of Springside conducted by outside organizations, as well as proposals and reports presented to Springside Landscape Restoration by those organizations. Included are records of an archeological survey of Springside conducted in the Fall of 2001 by the Vassar College Archaeological Field School, including dozens of samples collected by the students undertaking the field study, such as fragments of rock and glass, pottery shards, bones, and iron nails.
  Organized into three subseries: Proposals, Reports, and Surveys - Vassar College Archaeological Field School. Sub-arranged alphabetically by title.
- Series VI. Writings and Publications, 1950-2017; (Boxes 8-9)
  This series contains writings and publications related to Springside, Springside Landscape Restoration, Andrew Jackson Downing, and other related topics. Writings include published and unpublished drafts of essays, papers, and articles, as well as notes and short writings and summaries. Publications consist primarily of clippings and newsletters, including the newsletter of Springside Landscape Restoration.
  Arranged alphabetically by author or title.
- Series VII. Nelson Family Papers, 1870-2024; (Boxes 9, 11)
  This series contains materials collected by Miles Nelson that document his family's ownership of the Springside property after Matthew Vassar, including property records, notes, and photographs.
Container List
- Series I. Administrative Files, 1982-2019
  - Assisted living facility proposal, 1999 (Folder 1.1)
  - Brochures, undated (Folder 1.2)
  - Brochures - Events, 1993 (Folder 1.3)
  - Brochures - "Tree Trail,", undated (Folder 1.4)
  - Brochures - Walking Tour, circa 2004 (Folder 1.5)
  - By-Laws, 1987-1992 (Folder 1.6)
  - By-Laws, undated (Folder 1.7)
  - Charter amendment petition, 1992-1993 (Folder 1.8)
  - Correspondence, 1985 (Folder 1.9)
  - Correspondence, 1986-1987 (Folder 1.10)
  - Correspondence, 1988-1989 (Folder 1.11)
  - Correspondence, 1990-1992 (Folder 1.12)
  - Correspondence, 1993-1997 (Folder 1.13)
  - Correspondence, 1999-2003 (Folder 1.14)
  - Correspondence, 2004 (Folder 1.15)
  - Correspondence, 2005 (Folder 1.16)
  - Correspondence, 2008 (Folder 1.17)
  - Correspondence - Flad, Harvey, 1985-2017 (Folder 1.18)
  - Correspondence - Hartgen Archaeological Associates, 2004-2006 (Folder 1.19)
  - Correspondence - Hutchins, Everts, and Lefferts, 1988 (Folder 1.20)
  - Correspondence - Pierpont Associates, 1987-1988 (Folder 1.21)
  - Correspondence - Toole, Robert M., 1983-1986 (Folder 1.22)
  - Correspondence - Toole, Robert M., 1987-2001 (Folder 1.23)
  - Correspondence - Walmsley & Company, Inc., 1988-1989 (Folder 1.24)
  - Correspondence - William A. Hall Architecture and Planning, 1990-1995 (Folder 1.25)
  - Donor lists, 1999-2000 (Folder 1.26)
  - Drainage and hydrology, 1998-2000 (Folder 1.27)
  - Dutchess County Landmarks Association, 1983 (Folder 1.28)
  - Executive director, reports and memos, 1991-1992 (Folder 1.29)
  - Executive director search, 1990-1991 (Folder 1.30)
  - Event cards, 2006, undated (Folder 1.31)
  - "Existing Conditions Narrative,", undated (Folder 1.32)
  - Financial records, 1990 (Folder 1.33)
  - Financial records, 1991-1992 (Folder 1.34)
  - Financial records, 1993 (Folder 1.35)
  - "Flora and Fauna,", 2004-2006 (Folder 1.36)
  - Furlani lawsuit, 2002-2004 (Folder 1.37)
  - Gatehouse, 1987 (Folder 2.1)
  - General File, 1991 (Folder 2.2)
  - General File, 1992 (Folder 2.3)
  - General File, 1993 (Folder 2.4)
  - General File, 1994 (Folder 2.5)
  - General File, 1995 (Folder 2.6)
  - General File, 1996 (Folder 2.7)
  - General File, 1998 (Folder 2.8)
  - General File, 2002 (Folder 2.9)
  - General File, 2003 (Folder 2.10)
  - General File, 2004 (Folder 2.11)
  - General File, 2005 (Folder 2.12)
  - Heritage trail, 2002-2005 (Folder 2.13)
  - Hudson River Valley Greenway trails, 1988-1993 (Folder 2.14)
  - Hydraulic and hydrological features, 1999 (Folder 2.15)
  - Kouri lawsuit, 2004-2006 (Folder 2.16)
  - L.T. Bookout Inc, EQBA Appraisal agreement, 1992 (Folder 2.17)
  - Maintenance, 1997 (Folder 2.18)
  - Maintenance, 2004-2006 (Folder 2.19)
  - Maintenance/Restoration Binder, 2004 (Folders 2.20-2.21)
  - Meeting Minutes, 1986 (Folder 2.22)
  - Meeting Minutes, 1987 (Folder 2.23)
  - Meeting Minutes, 1988 (Folder 2.24)
  - Meeting Minutes, 1989 (Folder 2.25)
  - Meeting Minutes, 1990 (Folder 2.26)
  - Meeting Minutes, 1991 (Folder 2.27)
  - Meeting Minutes, 1992 Jan-Apr (Folder 2.28)
  - Meeting Minutes, 1992 May-Dec (Folder 2.29)
  - Meeting Minutes, 1993 (Folder 2.30)
  - Meeting Minutes, 1994 (Folder 3.1)
  - Meeting Minutes, 1995 (Folder 3.2)
  - Meeting Minutes, 1996 (Folder 3.3)
  - Meeting Minutes, 1997 (Folder 3.4)
  - Meeting Minutes, 1998 (Folder 3.5)
  - Meeting Minutes, 1999 (Folder 3.6)
  - Meeting Minutes, 2000 (Folder 3.7)
  - Meeting Minutes, 2001 (Folder 3.8)
  - Meeting Minutes, 2002 (Folder 3.9)
  - Meeting Minutes, 2003 (Folder 3.10)
  - Meeting Minutes, 2004 (Folder 3.11)
  - Meeting Minutes, 2005 (Folder 3.12)
  - Meeting Minutes, 2006 (Folder 3.13)
  - Meeting Minutes, 2008 (Folder 3.14)
  - Meeting Minutes, 2016 (Folder 9.24)
  - Meeting Minutes, 2019 (Folder 9.25)
  - New York State Department of Labor claim, 1992-1993; [RESTRICTED] (Folder 3.15)
  - New York State charities registration, 1991-1993 (Folder 3.16)
  - Nomination of Porter's Lodge to City of Poughkeepsie Historic District and Landmarks Preservation Commission, 2004 (Folder 3.17)
  - Notes, circa 1984 (Folder 3.18)
  - Oral history with Harold Knowlton, notes, 2004 Jul (Folder 3.19)
  - Personnel policy, 1990 (Folder 3.20)
  - Pest management, 2004 (Folder 3.21)
  - Pierpont Associates Fundraising case study, 1987-1988 (Folder 3.22)
  - "Plan of work,", undated (Folder 3.23)
  - "Preservation Maintenance Plan,", undated (Folder 3.24)
  - Projects: Adriance/Ivy Terrace drainage, 1998 (Folder 3.25)
  - Projects: Matthew Vassar statue at Springside, 2005 (Folder 3.26)
  - Projects: Porter's lodge painting, 1994 (Folder 3.27)
  - Projects: Porter's lodge painting, 2005, 2013 (Folder 3.28)
  - Projects: Porter's lodge painting, contracts with the City of Poughkeepsie, 1999-2000 (Folder 3.29)
  - Projects: Porter's lodge roof, 1996-1997 (Folder 3.30)
  - Projects: Signage and labels, 2005 (Folder 3.31)
  - Projects: Wall repair, 2005 (Folder 3.32)
  - Promotional materials, undated (Folder 3.33)
  - Public relations, 2004 (Folder 3.34)
  - "Restoration Concepts for Springside,", 1987 Sep, undated (Folder 3.35)
  - SavATree program, 1992 (Folder 3.36)
  - Request for Proposals, 1987 (Folder 3.37)
  - Site plans, undated (Folder 3.38)
  - Springside Associates Lawsuit - Agreement drafts, 1984 (Folder 3.39)
  - Springside Associates Lawsuit - City of Poughkeepsie, correspondence, 1983-1984 (Folder 3.40)
  - Springside Associates Lawsuit - City of Poughkeepsie Common Council, 1984 (Folder 3.41)
  - Springside Associates Lawsuit - City of Poughkeepsie Common Council, meeting minutes, 1984 Jan 16-30 (Folder 3.42)
  - Springside Associates Lawsuit - City of Poughkeepsie Planning Board, correspondence and memos, 1983 (Folder 3.43)
  - Springside Associates Lawsuit - City of Poughkeepsie Planning Board, meeting, audiocassettes, 1983 Nov 22; [2 tapes] (Folder 3.44)
  - Springside Associates Lawsuit - City of Poughkeepsie Planning Board, meeting minutes, 1983 Dec 6 (Folder 4.1)
  - Springside Associates Lawsuit - City of Poughkeepsie Planning Board, meeting transcript, 1984 Nov 22 (Folder 4.2)
  - Springside Associates Lawsuit - City of Poughkeepsie Planning Board, meeting minutes, special session on Springside, 1985 Jun 4 (Folder 4.3)
  - Springside Associates Lawsuit - City of Poughkeepsie Planning Board, staff report, 1983 Aug (Folder 4.4)
  - Springside Associates Lawsuit - City of Poughkeepsie Planning Board, memos and comments, 1982-1985 (Folder 4.5)
  - Springside Associates Lawsuit - Correspondence and meeting notes, 1982-1986 (Folder 4.6)
  - Springside Associates Lawsuit - Dutchess County Landmarks Association, 1982-1984 (Folder 4.7)
  - Springside Associates Lawsuit - Hudson River Sloop Clearwater, Inc., 1984-1986 (Folder 4.8)
  - Springside Associates Lawsuit - Legal documents - "Affidavit in support of the Petition,", 1984 Feb (Folder 4.9)
  - Springside Associates Lawsuit - Legal documents - "Consent to Change Attorney,", 1984 Nov 27 (Folder 4.10)
  - Springside Associates Lawsuit - Legal documents - "Exhibits to Petition,", 1983 (Folder 4.11)
  - Springside Associates Lawsuit - Legal documents - "Judgement,", 1984 May 18 (Folder 4.12)
  - Springside Associates Lawsuit - Legal documents - "Memorandum of Understanding,", 1984 Dec 6 (Folder 4.13)
  - Springside Associates Lawsuit - Legal documents - "Notice of Petition,", 1984 Feb 19 (Folder 4.14)
  - Springside Associates Lawsuit - Legal documents - "Opinion of Title,", 1984 Nov 21 (Folder 4.15)
  - Springside Associates Lawsuit - Legal documents - "Petitioner's Memo of Law in Support of the Petition,", 1984 (Folder 4.16)
  - Springside Associates Lawsuit - Legal documents - "Stipulation of Settlement,", 1984-1985 (Folder 4.17)
  - Springside Associates Lawsuit - Legal documents - "Supplemental Affidavit in Support of the Petition,", 1984 Apr 20 (Folder 4.18)
  - Springside Associates Lawsuit - Legal documents - "Verified Reply,", 1984 Apr 20 (Folder 4.19)
  - Springside Associates Lawsuit - Letters and statements to the City of Poughkeepsie Mayor, 1983-1984 (Folder 4.20)
  - Springside Associates Lawsuit - "Marketability Analysis of Proposed Springside Luxury Condominium Development,", 1982 Sep (Folder 4.21)
  - Springside Associates Lawsuit - New York State offices and departments, 1984 (Folder 4.22)
  - Springside Associates Lawsuit - Notes and research, 1983-1986 (Folder 4.23)
  - Springside Associates Lawsuit - Out of court settlement and modifications, 1983-1985 (Folder 4.24)
  - Springside Associates Lawsuit - Petition to City of Poughkeepsie Planning Board, 1983 Nov - 1984 Jan (Folder 4.25)
  - Springside Associates Lawsuit - Proposed subdivision, 1986-1989 (Folder 4.26)
  - Springside Associates Lawsuit - Springside Condominiums, Inc. - Agreement, 1990 Feb 15 (Folder 4.27)
  - Springside Associates Lawsuit - Springside Condominiums, Inc. - Brochure, circa 1986 (Folder 4.28)
  - Springside Associates Lawsuit - Springside Condominiums, Inc. - Memorandum of Understanding, 1992 Mar (Folder 4.29)
  - Springside Associates Lawsuit - Springside site plan modifications, 1986 (Folder 4.30)
  - Springside Associates Lawsuit - "Stipulation," drafts, 1984 (Folder 4.31)
  - Springside Associates Lawsuit - "Testimony of the Hudson River Sloop Clearwater, Inc.,", 1984 Feb 6 (Folder 4.32)
  - Springside Condominium, Inc., 1986-1991 (Folder 4.33)
  - Springside Landscape Restoration website, circa 2000 (Folder 4.34)
  - Springside Landscape Restoration website, 2016 (Folder 4.35)
  - Springside National Historic Landmark, 1984 (Folder 4.36)
  - Springside Quitclaim Deed, 1990 Feb 15 (Folder 4.37)
  - Sterling Properties Group, submission to City of Poughkeepsie Planning Board, 2005 Sep 7 (Folder 4.38)
  - Symposium on Andrew Jackson Downing, Dumbarton Oaks, Philadelphia, 1987 (Folder 4.39)
  - Tax exempt certificate 509(a), 1989 (Folder 4.40)
  - Tax exempt status, 1987-1993 (Folder 4.41)
  - Tax exempt status - Property tax, 1990-1991 (Folder 5.1)
  - Tree survey, [2004?] (Folder 5.2)
  - Walking tours, circa 2004-2009 (Folder 5.3)
  - Yankee Intern Program, 1988 (Folder 5.4)
- Series II. Grants, 1987-2005
  - Chronology and research, 2000-2003 (Folder 5.5)
  - Americorps, 1997 (Folder 5.6)
  - Andy Warhol Foundation, 1996 (Folder 5.7)
  - Central Hudson (for Hemlock treatment), 1993 (Folder 5.8)
  - City of Poughkeepsie, Community Development Block Grant, 1997, 2003 (Folder 5.9)
  - Community Foundation of Dutchess County, 2002-2003 (Folder 5.10)
  - Cunneen-Hackett Charitable Trust, 1992 (Folder 5.11)
  - Dyson Foundation, 2001-2002 (Folder 5.12)
  - Getty Grant Program, 1990 (Folder 5.13)
  - Hudson River Improvement Fund, 1992-1996 (Folder 5.14)
  - Hudson River Valley Greenway Conservancy, 1992-1994 (Folder 5.15)
  - Hudson River Valley Greenway Conservancy, 2002-2005 (Folder 5.16)
  - IBM Cash Grant, 1992 (Folder 5.17)
  - IBM Equipment Grant, 1991 (Folder 5.18)
  - J. M. Kaplan Fund, 1991-1993 (Folder 5.19)
  - James J. McCann Charitable Trust, 1992 (Folder 5.20)
  - National Park Service, 2002 (Folder 5.21)
  - National Recreational Trails Program, 2002 (Folder 5.22)
  - New York Council for the Humanities, 1996-1997 (Folder 5.23)
  - New York State Council on the Arts, 1988-1990 (Folder 5.24)
  - New York State legislature members, 1993-1995 (Folder 5.25)
  - New York State Office of Parks, Recreation, and Historic Preservation, 1994-1996 (Folder 5.26)
  - New York State Office of Parks, Recreation, and Historic Preservation - Environmental Quality Bond Act (EQBA), application, 1987 (Folder 5.27)
  - New York State Office of Parks, Recreation, and Historic Preservation - Environmental Quality Bond Act (EQBA), proposal and acquisition checklist, 1987-1991 (Folder 5.28)
  - New York State Office of Parks, Recreation, and Historic Preservation - Environmental Quality Bond Act (EQBA), 1988-1992 (Folder 5.29)
  - New York State Office of Parks, Recreation, and Historic Preservation - Environmental Quality Bond Act (EQBA), 1991-1992 (Folder 5.30)
  - New York State Office of Parks, Recreation, and Historic Preservation - Environmental Quality Bond Act (EQBA), vouchers and payments, 1992 (Folder 5.31)
  - New York State Office of Parks, Recreation, and Historic Preservation - Environmental Quality Bond Act (EQBA), revocation of funds, 1993 (Folder 5.32)
  - Preservation League of New York State, 1988-1993 (Folder 5.33)
  - Preservation League of New York State, 1995-2004 (Folder 5.34)
  - Research, 1991-1993 (Folder 5.35)
- Series III. Photographs, 1972-2006
  - Springside, taken by Rollie McKenna for National Historic Landmark registration, 1969 (printed), undated (Folder 6.1)
  - Springside buildings, polaroids, 1972 Jul 30 (Folder 6.2)
  - Springside buildings, 1972-2004 (Folder 6.3)
  - Springside site and buildings, 1975 (Folder 6.4)
  - Springside buildings, [circa 1980s] (Folder 6.5)
  - Springside "existing conditions," negatives, 1987 Apr (Folder 6.6)
  - Springside, with map index, 1987 Apr; [127 photographs] (Folder 6.7)
  - Springside buildings, 1988 (Folder 6.8)
  - Springside site, 1991 May (Folder 6.9)
  - Springside site and buildings, 1991 Sep (Folder 6.10)
  - Springside plaque unveiling, 1991 Oct (Folder 6.11)
  - Springside site, prints and negatives, 1992 Jan-Mar (Folder 6.12)
  - Springside cocktail party, Camp Deacon workers, 1992 Jul (Folder 6.13)
  - Hudson Valley Leadership - Dutchess Community College classes at Springside, prints and negatives, circa 1993 (Folder 6.14)
  - Springside site and buildings, negatives, circa 1993 (Folder 6.15)
  - Springside events, 1994 (Folder 6.16)
  - Springside clean-up days, 1994 Apr-Jul (Folder 6.17)
  - Springside site and events, 1995 (Folder 6.18)
  - Springside clean-up and plant sale, 1995 May (Folder 6.19)
  - Springside, overhead views and diagrams, 1996, undated (Folder 6.20)
  - [Matthew Vassar cottage façade exhibit, New York State Museum, Albany?], [2001?] (Folder 6.21)
  - Springside plant sale and debris dumping, 2001 (Folder 6.22)
  - Springside plant sale and work, 2002 May; [1 CD] (Folder 6.23)
  - Springside sign installation, 2003 (Folder 6.24)
  - Springside site survey, 2006 Mar (Folder 6.25)
  - 113 and 121 Academy St, Poughkeepsie, NY, undated (Folder 6.26)
  - Downing, Andrew Jackson, illustrations (reproductions), undated (Folder 6.27)
  - Springside, undated (Folder 6.28)
  - Springside, architectural designs by Andrew Jackson Downing (reproductions), undated (Folder 6.29)
  - Springside, illustrations (reproductions), undated (Folder 6.30)
- Series IV. Site Plans and Maps, 1983-2000
  - Harry J. Bly
    - "Springside - Subdivision of Lands," revised, 1986 Aug 19 (Folder 11.1 (Oversize))
    - "Subdivision Plan of Lands of Springside Associates," revised, 1983 Sep 15; [2 copies] (Folder 11.1 (Oversize))
    - Untitled Springside plan, revised, 1985 Nov 7 (Folder 11.1 (Oversize))
  - Michael George and Lisa Dreishpoon-Weiss